Natalie Ortiz

p: (210) 744-2384 | e: ndnatalie@gmail.com | Github: natalieortiz | LinkedIn: ndnatalie | ndnatalie.com

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer making a career change from sales and support into a programming role focusing on back-end development. Equipped with past experience from tech companies like Apple and Rackspace to contribute to productive, project-focused team environment. Currently furthering knowledge base by powering through the Laracasts catalog.

TECHNICAL TOOLBOX

HTML | CSS | Twitter Bootstrap | JavaScript | ¡Query | MySQL | PHP | Laravel | Git & Github

EDUCATION

Codeup, San Antonio, TX – 2016

Completed 16-week project-based immersion program in full-stack technologies to accelerate web development skills. Spent 480+ hours studying modern web technologies and building real projects.

University of Notre Dame, Notre Dame, IN – 2003

Obtained Bachelor of Business Administration in Management Information Systems.

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

<u>Weather Finder</u> – Utilized JavaScript, jQuery, Google Maps API to allow a user to find a location using an in-browser map or search bar. Google Maps then geocodes data into coordinates and provides user with a 3-day weather forecast.

<u>Whack-a-weenie</u> – Developed custom whack-a-mole game using JavaScript and jQuery. The user has 30 seconds to hit as many dogs as possible. Used Twitter Bootstrap to integrate a modal response with an embedded YouTube video when user achieves a high score.

<u>Ad-lister Project</u> – Led 3-person team to create a Craigslist clone in PHP and HTML. Primarily responsible for the back-end functionality of the website utilizing homegrown framework. Used MySQL to generate and maintain the databases and PHP to provide the logic for the user to display, edit, and create ads.

ADDITIONAL COMPETENCIES

Sales Administration

- Produced and delivered weekly sales reports to track market objectives.
- Utilized Salesforce to service customer accounts and track sales metrics for sales leaders.

Product

- Managed and tracked inventory forecasts as requested by Product Management.
- Provided administrative and project support to any large scale Product Management projects like SKU rationalization or new product roll-outs.
- Set up SKUs and modified SKU attributes through Data Management Database.

Marketing

 Served as administrator for company website. Adding and removing products & specification sheets, and making changes to existing products on the website through content management software.

WORK HISTORY

Ventev Wireless Infrastructure- San Antonio, TX - *Sales Support Representative*, 2014 - 2016

Peddle.com - Austin, TX- *Loyalty Agent,* 2012 - 2013

Apple, Inc. - Austin, TX- Mac Expert, 2011 - 2012

Clear - San Antonio, TX- Market Support Representative, 2009 - 2010

Museo Alameda - San Antonio, TX - Development Coordinator, 2008 - 2009

Rackspace - San Antonio, TX- Project Coordinator, Recruiting Coordinator, 2005 - 2008